If we want to include data that doesn't exist in both tables,
如果我们想展示的数据并未同时存在于两张表格
but only in one of the two tables we are using in our joint statement,
而只存在于其中一张表格
there are three types of joins we might use: a left join,
我们有三种连接类型可用 Left Join、
a right join, and a full outer join.
Right join 以及 Full Outer Join
Each of these joins will provide all the resulting rows of an inner join,
每种 Join 都会显示 Inner Join 的所有结果行
but we may also gain some additional rows.
并额外包含一些其他行
So, the result of an outer join will always have at least as many rows as an inner join,
所以 Outer Join 的结果数至少与 Inner Join 的结果数相同
with the same logic in the, on, clause.
只要有相同的 ON 子句
This video is going to focus primarily on left and right joins.
本视频将着重讲述 Left 与 Right Join
When we read our SELECT statements,
在我们的 SELECT 语句中
the table listed in the FROM statement is considered the left table,
FROM 语句中列出的表格被看作左表
while the table in the join is considered the right table.
而 JOIN 中的表格为右表
Let's change our inner join into a left join,
让我们把 Inner Join 改为 Left Join
by simply writing the word, left.
只需要简单地写下 LEFT
The results that we get back,
这样我们得到的结果
will include all of the results that match with the right table,
包括了能匹配右表的所有结果
just like in an inner join.
这部分与 Inner Join 的结果一样
It will also return any results that are in the left table that did not match.
同时它还会返回左表中没有匹配项的所有结果
Using these subsets of the accounts and orders tables,
使用这些账户和订单表格的子集
every single row in the orders table here,
这个订单表格中的每一行
can be matched to a row in the accounts table,
都可以匹配到账户表格的对应行
with an ID in the accounts table,
因为账户表格中的 id
that corresponds to an account ID in the orders table.
与订单表格的 account_id 相对应
This result set is exactly the same as if we had used an inner join.
这个结果集与 Inner Join 完全一致
A right join would produce a different set of results, though.
而 Right Join 的结果则会不太一样
There are four accounts without any orders,
这里有四个没有订单的账户
which means four rows of data that do not satisfy the condition of this join.
意味着有四行数据不满足 Join 的条件
Since it's a right join and not an inner join,
因为现在是 Right Join 而不是 Inner Join
these rows will be included at the bottom of the result set.
所以这几行也会显示在结果集的底部
They don't match with rows in the left table,
由于它们在左表中没有匹配的行
so any columns from the left table will contain no data for these rows.
所以左表中的列中不会包含这些行的数据
We'll discuss more about what this means soon enough.
我们之后会进一步探讨这意味着什么
You can see that after we join,
你可以看到 在连接之后
this final table has all the same rows as the original inner join table.
最终的表格包含了 Inner Join 表格的行
But it has these extra rows from
但同时底部列出了账户表格中
the accounts table at the bottom that were not matched with any orders.
没有与订单相匹配的行
Left and right joins are somewhat interchangeable.
Left Join 和 Right Join 在某些情况是可以互换的
If we change this query so that the accounts table is in the FROM clause,
如果我们更改此次查询 把账户表格放在 FROM 子句
and the orders table is in the join clause,
把订单表格放在 JOIN 子句
the extra rows will be in the left table.
那左表会显示额外几行内容
We can now run a left join,
现在我们运行 Left Join
and the results will be exactly the same as
这样的结果与我们之前查询进行的 Right Join
the right join we did with the previous query.
是完全一致的
Because left and right joins are effectively interchangeable,
因为 Left 和 Right Join 是完全可以互换的
we use left joins through the rest of this course.
接下来的课程中我们会使用 Left Join 作为例子
The world is by and large standardized around this behavior,
通常来说 这是世界通用的标准选择
so you'll rarely see a right join in the wild.
很少会看到使用 Right Join 的
This makes it easier to read other people's queries,
这样才能比较轻松地阅读其他人的查询
and quickly understand what they intended to accomplish.
快速了解他们想要完成什么任务
Consistency is especially important if you're writing a query with multiple joins.
如果你使用多个 JOIN 编写一个查询 要尤其注意保证使用 JOIN 时的一致性
We're not quite there yet, but we will be soon.
现在我们还达不到这个阶段 但很快就可以了